High school is no fun.
I wanna go back to middle school.
MIDDLE SCHOOL
ALUMNI GATHERING
That's all you keep saying.
Nothing beats the old homestead.
No one uses that word anymore, do they?
Your friends came with you
to the culture festival, right?
Individually, all my friends
are good people.
But I just don't vibe with
the overall feel of the school.
Is it gloomy?
Yes!
It always feels like there's
this empty silence!
And there's an overwhelming
lack of idiots.
How are we supposed
to take that statement?
I don't mean academically.
I mean the fun kind.
Third year of middle school after
classes was the best, wasn't it?
When the three of us—me, Yamada, and Miyu—
did that after-school study group.
That was seriously so much fun.
AH HA HA
HEE HEE
You mean the one where we
basically just talked, right?
All I remember is rolling with laughter
at conversations with no substance.
Exactly! That's what I liked!
His vehemence is scary.
We were students testing into high school,
but we had no after-school activities,
leaving us with such a sense of freedom!
That rush of emotion from thinking,
"Let's graduate without any regrets!"
The afternoon sun shining into
the classroom... The melancholy feels...
He's monologuing.
POUT
Although, Yamada got a girlfriend
partway through and stopped coming.
For real, right?
Hey! That doesn't make me
the bad guy here!
FLASHBACK TO
THE PREVIOUS EPISODE...
Sometimes, around dusk,
for no reason, I'll take a walk down
the route I took to middle school.
You okay?
When I hear them singing choir
songs we sang in middle school,
I really feel like I'm about to cry.
He's not okay.
When you're having fun in the moment,
you don't realize how lucky
you are to be in that environment.
...is what Ricchan was saying.
I feel like he must have it pretty rough.
What?
He's just too hung up on the past!
That's cold.
I can't empathisize with someone saying
"middle school was too much fun."
And why was Suzuki attending
this gathering like it was normal?
You okay with that, Tani?
Yeah. I think it's probably fine.
And overthinking everything
makes it seem like I don't trust her,
which feels disrespectful.
Thanks for being worried about us.
Why are you getting more confident?
Is that bad?
Monster.
DON'T LEAVE ME
BEHIND, TANI...
What?
YOU AND I ARE POLAR OPPOSITES
What are you getting?
I'm in the mood for chicken curry.
Then I think I'll get
the chicken hayashi.
Now that I think about it,
there's this guy, too.
I might be headed toward
falling in love right now!
What happened after that?
Did he make any progress?
No. I won't ask any questions
until Yamada brings it up himself.
If it didn't go well,
I have nothing I can say to him.
And even if it did go well,
I still have nothing to say!
(BECAUSE
I'D
FEEL
CONFLICTED
ABOUT
IT)
I'm just so...
STAND-IN COMMENTATOR
On the day of the culture festival,
this is what happened to Yamada!
Is this one you took?
Yes.
Really? Wow.
SILENCE . . .
What do I do?
I'm nervous again,
so this conversation isn't...
"I'm sorry my replies to the messages you
sent over summer break were so awful."
"I'm sorry that it seemed like
I was rejecting you."
Um, I...
You know...
Please, go ahead!
I'm sorry.
What?
For texting you... and everything else.
If you're not close, wouldn't it be scary
to suddenly be asked for contact info?
I thought maybe I've been too pushy.
Like, given the distance
between us and stuff.
I'll think a little more before I act.
I'm sorry.
Nishi-san, what were you going to say?
Um...
I'm sorry too.
My phone... Up until now,
I've used it to contact my parents,
and once in a while, I message Hon-chan
or other girls I'm friends with,
but that's all.
I overthink about whether
I've written anything weird
or made typos, and it slows me down.
And yet, I still send
ridiculously long texts.
And then I think too much about what
would happen if I went silent on a call.
But...
It wasn't that I didn't like it.
Being scared of making mistakes
makes me overthink everything.
I want to be able
to not overthink so much.
You and I are polar opposites.
When you sent something,
it made me so happy that
I'd reply right away without thinking.
I never thought you wrote anything weird.
Thank goodness
And I'm nowhere near as concerned about
details as you think I am, Nishi-san.
Oh!
You should just make mistakes! With me.
What?
WHAT?!
Because I'm not someone you need
to be careful around at all.
We're peers, right?
And if I'm being annoying,
you can just say, "Ugh, what a pain!"
And if I'm making too much noise,
you can just say, "Shut up, stupid!"
I wouldn't say that! Not that way.
"You're being entirely too loud."
I'm not that elegant.
RIHITO
INCOMING CALL
Ricchan! I forgot!
I'm gonna head out. Thanks!
Is it okay for me
to talk to you at school?
Of course!
Then let's talk again!
And thus, they managed
to make a little progress.
Ever since the culture festival,
he's been in an oddly good mood,
and he's clearly been looking for
someone while we've been here.
I'm not gonna bite. I won't bite!
Yamada-kun, are you looking for someone?
Huh? Oh.
Gapacho.
I'm not biting! You hear me?!
I won't think about it.
But I mean...
Both Yamada and Tani
are good guys to begin with.
THINKING
ABOUT IT
Of course there's someone who likes them,
and they're able to accept that.
Sorry, Taira-kun.
Your personality's kinda different
than I thought it was.
Don't remember stuff you hate.
What that friend of Yamada's said...
that middle school was so much
fun and high school isn't.
Basically, it's a contrast thing.
Not being able to choose your elementary
or middle school makes them more hellish.
Even if he acknowledged that,
from my perspective, I'd still be jealo—
MOUTHING
FLAP
You weren't saying anything?
I tricked you! I tricked you!
I tricked you!
Don't interfere with my music time!
And don't you laugh.
I'm not laughing.
Laugh.
OTHERWISE THERE'S
NO POINT IN MY
GETTING TRICKED...
What?
Taira doesn't usually head
toward the station.
That means he must be working today.
Das right.
Then I guess I'll head to the convenience
store before going home! Okay, Tani-kun?
Why?
Sure.
Don't just say "sure."
We'll only stop by for a little while,
so make us some soft serve!
We don't have a machine
for that at our shop.
And when we get there,
it'll still be the shift before mine.
What?
Tani-kun, can you wait for him?
Just go home.
Hmm...
That's where you hesitate?
You're so funny!
Why do you only come
when I'm there, anyway?
Huh?
Because it's more fun
when you're there, right?
Right, Tani-kun?
Yeah.
Huh. Is that so?
Well, I guess it's fine.
The ice cream I just bought was a winner!
Hurry up and go home!
Yamada-kun!
What do I do? D-Do I say hello?
BA-DUMP
M-Me, talk first? Can I do that?
You should just make mistakes! With me.
BA-DUMP
Okay!
Oh! Nishi-san!
Eek!
GLOOM...
"Eek"?
Oh, no, um...
I was fully determined to say
hello to you, but you said it first.
What's that about? It's funny that
you were determined about it.
He thinks what I did was funny.
SAVE
H-Hon-chan!
Good morning.
Morning.
Good. Morning.
What's with that face?
In spite of everything,
you seem to be getting along well!
So, Nisshi...
what do you think of Yamada so far?
What?
My heart pounds.
But...
But what?
I don't know how to put it...
I wonder what this feeling could be.
BA-DUMP...
There are people in real life
who actually say that!
I'VE SEEN IT...
I'VE SEEN IT BEFORE...
You mean like, "I wonder what this
tingling in the depths of my chest is"?
Oh, no. It's nothing so fancy.
Not fancy.
I don't know if it's Yamada-kun or the
situation that is making my heart pound.
Urk....
Wow. That's a lot more realistic
than I thought it would be.
My experience in talking with
boys is so drastically lacking that
my heart pounds really hard and it's
difficult to know why it's pounding.
Even if it wasn't Yamada-kun, I think
my heart would still pound like that.
Dear, dear. I see.
Still, I'm relieved to know that
you aren't too dense a heroine.
Sorry. Don't mind me.
Actually, even if the situation is what
has you going, that's not an issue, is it?
What? But... doesn't that make it
seem like anyone would do?
But there's no point in
thinking about that, is there?
What?
Basically, in the case that your heart is
pounding because of the situation,
the question of whether your heart would
pound if it was someone other than Yamada
is what you get hung up on, right?
It is.
Nisshi, at the present moment,
do you have this "someone else"?
No, I don't.
Then, aren't you comparing Yamada
to something that doesn't exist?
"But what if things were like this..."
That's a worry that you
created out of nothing,
and you can create
those infinitely, right?
If you're going to be bothered by
something, better reality than what-ifs.
Wouldn't it be better to go with a simple,
"How do I feel about this person?"
I-I see. That's true.
Then, first, I need to be able
to talk without getting nervous.
In the end, that's always the thing.
BACK TO THE START AGAIN
Heave-ho!
Don't worry! Whether it's a boy or
a girl, in the end, everyone's human.
Hon-chan is kind of scary sometimes.
You'll get used to it over time.
And whether your heart's pounding
because you're nervous and shy...
or because of the irregular situation,
or because of a specific person...
I hope you'll figure out
what's causing it.
Yeah.
Hon-chan, you don't get shy around
people at all, do you? I'm so jealous.
It's not even not being shy.
Regardless of gender, I basically
vaguely dislike anyone I don't know.
But that's...
Thank you for your work today.
Thank you for yours.
Tani-kun...
Up until now, he hasn't said much,
so I didn't know what he was thinking,
which scared me a little,
and my heart was pounding.
But because we talked a little
at the culture festival,
I'm not as nervous
with him as I was before.
THAT WAS
"BEING SHY"
HEART POUNDING...
Oh, come on, Suzuki!
It went inside the building!
AN "EVEN THE GOING-HOME
CLUB WANTS TO EXERCISE!"  GATHERING
(HELD IRREGULARLY)
That doesn't count!
That was the wind's fault, I tell you!
Tani-kun?
And Nishi-san!
Yoo-hoo!
Huh?
Suzuki, since when did you
and Nishi-san become friends?
Huh? What does it matter? It's fine.
Right, Nissan?
What?
GOT SWEPT ALONG INTO GOING HOME TOGETHER PART OF THE WAY
Was it really all right for me
to go with them?
BA-DUMP
PANIC
WORRY
Were you playing badminton the whole time?
Yes. Badminton.
I may be in the Going-Home Club,
HEH
but I have to exercise sometimes
or my sense for it dulls.
When was it ever sharp?
Don't talk like you're
some kind of master.
You're already a super slow runner, right?
HNGH....
Which Suzuki are you speaking of?
Oh? Was that funny?
The way the antonym of "dull"
came up so quickly was funny.
That's what was funny?
It's kind of cold, isn't it?
My sweat's giving me chills.
Right?
Hang on! This is bad! Do I reek of sweat?
Huh? Yamada, are you the type
to worry about stuff like that?
Yes, I am! And don't talk in harmony!
Hey, Nishi-san,
you laugh a lot, don't you?
What?
HE NOTICED...
I'm so embarrassed.
BA-DUMP
THUMP
This is the nervous kind
of heart pounding.
BA-DUMP
THUMP
Um... I-I want to fix that about myself,
but I just can't help it.
Why?
That's crazy good, isn't it?
You're definitely better off
the way you are!
The nervous type of...
Yamada, if you're worried about
the smell of your sweat,
you can use the rest of this.
Huh? Thank you.
Satou, what scent is this?
PSHHHHH
Huh? Cool mint.
It's freezing!
What is this?!
My whole body's crazy cold now!
That's why I don't use it anymore
and you can use it up.
You're just using me to get rid of it!
The fact that I laugh easily
is part of it,
but it's also because Yamada-kun is
someone who creates a fun atmosphere.
See?
WHABAM-THUMP
Wait, what? What?
BA-DUMP
THMP
THUMP...
Tani-kun! G-Good morning.
Morning.
Okay! I was able to say
good morning naturally.
WHEW
I'm so sleepy!
BA-DUMPPPPP ! !
FWOOSH
What was that?
Oh! Tani, morning!
What was that just now?
Tani-kun, what were you
and Nishi-san talking about?
Huh? Nishi-san? Where?
Nothing. We said good morning. That's all.
Just normal stuff? You didn't do anything
that would make her panic and run away?
No.
Really?
Hey, Tani-kun?
What kind of girl is Nishi-san?
What?
Tani-kun, you do library work, so you've
been around her for some time now.
Have you talked about
lots of stuff together?
No, not at all.
SILENCE
I see.
He says the limited-time
beef katsu roll is sold out.
SHOPPING AT THE SCHOOL LUNCH COUNTER
Confound it.
Hey, Taira-kun? Can I ask
your advice about something?
Huh?
Asking me for advice?
A-About what?
Suzuki is excessively interested in a girl
who serves on the committee with you?
Yes. She seems to have something specific
in mind, but I don't really understand.
I mean, it's gotta be that, right?
She finds you suspicious.
WHAT...?
Me?
Yup. You two seem like
you get along, right?
Jealousy. It's jealousy.
What?
I haven't done anything
to make her jealous.
Actually, it's hard to imagine
Suzuki-san feeling that way at all.
YAY
Yay!
He has a point.
Well, if Suzuki really is jealous,
then it's probably about
not paying enough attention to her.
It's okay for you to be angry, Tani.
Come on. Get angry!
*THIS IS
TAIRA'S
SENSE OF
FAIRNESS
Do you want us to fight?
Could it be that you'd
be happy if she was jealous?
Oh, I see. I see. That makes sense.
A part of you wants to think that she's
jealous, even though it's hard to imagine.
But you don't have enough confidence
in yourself to declare it with certainty.
Is that it?
It's not like that.
Is it?
Wait...
It's you guys.
BA-DUMP
SHOCK
When did you guys get so friendly?
PANT
GASP
GASP...
PANT
GASP
GASP...
PANT
You're really that surprised?
I'm not sure why, but I'm sorry.
AFTER SCHOOL
Tani-kun, you have
library duty again today, right?
Yes.
And Nishi-san will be there, naturally?
Really? Roger that.
Suzuki-san, is something
bothering you about...
Yay! Yay! Yay!
Look! Look!
YEEEEEEAH
BAAAAAM
I bought all kinds of stuff!
MISCELLANEOUS SHELF-WORN TOYS
CLEARANCE SALE!
Wow! This is awesome!
Yamada! Look at this!
See?
Whoa! That's crazy!
WOW
YAY
I missed the timing to ask her.
WHOA
WOW
YAY
WORRY
REQUEST
I was able to greet Tani-kun, but
the moment I saw Yamada-kun, I ran away.
And when I was finally able to talk to
him a little better than I did before.
I'm going backwards.
Could it be that you'd be happy
if she was jealous?
That's...
ABSOLUTELY
DOES NOT APPLY
DOES NOT
QUITE APPLY
NEITHER
APPLIES
SOMEWHAT
ABSOLUTELY
APPLIES
MENTAL SURVEY SHEET
That's no good.
If one person's concern makes the other
person feel happy in their heart,
then that relationship isn't equal.
And actually...
Even if you can't be totally clear,
or if you're still thinking...
If you feel anxious and unsettled
for some reason, just tell me that.
I feel that way, too.
ANXIOUS
WORRY
If there's something she wants
to say, I want her to say it.
WORRY
And there's nothing for Suzuki-san
to feel uneasy about to begin with.
It would be my own dishonor
if she suspected me of something.
At this rate,
I'm certain I'm going to end up with
the same regrets I had over summer break.
Next time, I have to
make sure not to run away.
Wondering what she's planning,
what she's feeling...
I won't find the answer
thinking on my own.
Getting self-conscious for no reason
and panicking on my own is so unseemly.
The next time I see her...
The next time I see him...
I will ask her.
I will talk to him.
BA-DUMP
Oh! Nishi-san!
And Tani!
Good work on your shift!
Nice work!
Talk. Talk!
Wait... What do I do? Now that the moment
is here, I can't look him in the eye.
Suzuki-san.
Nissan!
Do you like bubbles?
We've already played with
a bunch of stuff,
so right now, we're having a bubble-fest!
A bubble-fest.
You can use this if you'd like!
Yamada's got the bubble liquid!
What?
Thank you!
Squeeze
I gratefully accept!
So formal!
Come on over!
Back then...
Hey, Nishi-san,
you laugh a lot, don't you?
What?
Now that I think about it...
I might be headed toward
falling in love right now!
INFORMATION ON
THE GIRL GLEANED FROM
CONVERSATIONS UP TO NOW
Same school, different class, shy...
SAME SCHOOL
DIFFERENT CLASS
SHY
MATCHES THE PROFILE
Why?
That's crazy good, isn't it?
You're definitely better off
the way you are!
THUMP
Is it Nishi-san? Is it Nishi-san, Yamada?!
Then, this morning...
FWOOSH
What was that?
Oh! Tani, morning!
What was that just now?
Her face went bright red and she ran?
After seeing Yamada?
This is already...
definitely mutual love, right?
Yay! Keep going! That's amazing!
I'm so glad I kept Yamada here
until the library closed.
Suzuki-san, is the reason you asked about
Nishi-san so many times today because...
What? Oh!
I wanted to know more
about what kind of girl she is.
I mean, we want to be friends, right?
What kind of girl is Nishi-san?
She meant it exactly the way she said it.
Huh? What? What's wrong?
EMBARRASSED
Are you okay? Do you feel sick?
Kill me.
Why?!
Nishi-san, sorry about Suzuki
being so pushy.
Not at all! This is fun!
Someone should be nice and watch Yamada.
He's working really hard for some reason.